(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-27T22:47:07.569797",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あ、あ、あ、皆様ー！
Ah, ah, ah, everyone!
うわー！
Whoa~!
いいね、コメント元気だね。
Nice, the comments are full of energy!
本日は風真いろは生誕ライブ2026「Wind Trails」にご来場いただきまして...
Thank you so much for coming to Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026 "Wind Trails" today...
誠にありがとうございます！
...thank you so very much!
イエーイ！
Yay!
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Before we begin, I'd like to share a few requests and announcements with everyone.
開演中、カメラやスマートフォンなどは...
During the show, regarding cameras and smartphones...
電源切られると見れなくなって困るので、電源は切らず...
...if you turn off the power you won't be able to watch, so please keep them on...
写真撮影などね、大量にしていただき...
...and feel free to take tons of photos...
当配信のハッシュタグ #風真いろは生誕ライブ2026 で...
...and using the stream's hashtag #KazamaIrohaBirthdayLive2026...
SNSに大量に画像ポストしてください！
...please post lots of pictures on SNS!
目指せ、Xトレンド1位！よろしくお願いします！
Let me aim for #1 on X trends! I appreciate your support!
あ、あの、でもスマホね、いっぱい写真撮ったりすると...
Ah, but you know, if you take lots of photos on your phone...
充電無くなっちゃいそうなので...
...your battery might run out...
スマホで見ている勢は、充電しっかりしてくださいね！
...so those watching on your phones, make sure you're well-charged!
はい、そしてその2！
Alright, and rule number two!
激しく頭を振る...
Violently headbanging...
激しくペンライトを振る、などはですね...
...or aggressively swinging your penlight...
あなた様のご自宅を破壊する危険性がございますので...
...carries the risk of damaging your home...
破壊されましても、こちらでは責任は一切負えませんので...
...and even if it gets damaged, we take no responsibility whatsoever...
お気をつけてください。ダメだよ、みんな！
...so please be careful. Don't do it, okay, everyone!
あ、そしてあと、もう1個！その3！
Ah, and one more thing! Number three!
今からハヤシライスを作ろうとしてる奴は間に合わないからやめな！
If anyone's trying to cook Hayashi rice right now, you won't make it in time, so stop!
絶対間に合わないから！
You definitely won't make it in time!
まあね、何か食べたり飲んだりしながら、ぜひね、ゆっくり楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
Well, feel free to sit back and enjoy the show while eating or drinking!
それでは、もうそろそろ始まるので...
Now then, it's almost time to start...
今しばらくお待ちください。
...so please wait just a little longer.
最後まで見てねー！
Please watch until the end!
風真いろは 生誕ライブ 2026
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026!
いくよー！
Here we go!
いっせーのーで 鳴り響いた スタートの合図
The sound of a starting signal rang out at once,
なぞった線で 結んだ世界
a world connected by a traced line.
色付けていく ここから
I'll start adding color from here.
物心つく頃 すでに此処にあった
It was already here when I became old enough to know better.
僕じゃない誰かの記憶は 夕陽と共に蘇る
Someone else's memories, not mine, start to revive along with the sunset.
古ぼけた絵本を取り出して
I took out an old, worn-out picture book,
落書きの中に1つの答えを見つけた
and found an answer in the doodles.
自分の価値に目を疑って どこまでだって堕ちていけるの
Doubting my own worth, how far can I fall?
どこか遠くに消えてしまいたい こんな世界じゃ僕はいらない
I want to disappear somewhere far away; I don't need myself in a world like this.
カウントダウンは始まっているよ
The countdown has already begun.
いっせーのーで声を上げて 聴こえてくるんだ
Shout out "Ready, set, go!", and I can hear it.
自分の影の長さに気づく もうこんな時間だ
I notice the length of my own shadow; it's already this late.
一等星が顔を出した 届きそうで手を伸ばした
The first-magnitude star appeared, and I reached out as if I could reach it.
次は僕についてきなよ どんな暗闇でも
"Next time, come with me," I said, no matter how dark it is.
(もういいかい？ まーだだよ)
(Ready yet? Not yet!)
幕は上がりだした
The curtain has started to rise.
(もういいかい？ まーだだよ)
(Ready yet? Not yet!)
色付けていく ここから
I'll start adding color from here.
10年後の僕らはすれ違いばかりで
Ten years later, we only pass each other by,
幻想に想いを馳せては 「戻れない」そう思い込んだ
letting our thoughts run wild in fantasy, concluding "We can't go back."
くたびれた心に追い打ちを
Adding another blow to my weary heart,
あの頃と変わらない夕陽も なんとも思わない
I think nothing of the sunset, unchanged from that time.
自分を信じ歩いていければ どこまでだって昇れるのにな
If I could believe in myself and keep walking, I could climb anywhere...
カットを跨ぐその空白に 大切なモノ見落としている
In that blank space that skips across cuts, I'm overlooking something important.
見つけられないと泣きわめく君へ
To you, who wails that you can't find it...
いっせーのーで声を上げて 聴こえてくるんだ
Shout out "Ready, set, go!", and I can hear it.
自分の影の長さに気づく もうこんな時間だ
I notice the length of my own shadow; it's already this late.
一等賞で駆け抜ける君 くっついていただけの僕でも
You, who run through in first place—even for me, who just clung to you,
君の前を歩けるかな？ こんな頼りない僕でも
can I walk in front of you? Even a person as unreliable as me...
宝箱はホコリをかぶったまま
The treasure chest remained covered in dust.
無くなった鍵はずっと 君のポケットの中にあった
The lost key was always inside your pocket.
散らばっていた全てが 今ひとつに重なる
Everything that was scattered now overlaps into one.
手を取り始めよう 僕たちの物語
Let's start taking hands; this is our story.
一度はいらないと思った
I once thought I didn't need it,
今なら胸を張れる気がしたんだ
but now I feel like I can hold my head high.
愛おしくて
Because I love you so much...
掛け声はいつも
The shout is always—
いっせーのーで声を上げて
Shout out "Ready, set, go!"
いっせーのーで声を上げて 聴こえてくるんだ
Shout out "Ready, set, go!", and I can hear it.
自分の影の長さに気づく もうこんな時間だ
I notice the length of my own shadow; it's already this late.
一等星が顔を出した 届きそうで手を伸ばした
The first-magnitude star appeared, and I reached out as if I could reach it.
次は僕についてきなよ どんな暗闇でも
"Next time, come with me," I said, no matter how dark it is.
(もういいかい？ まーだだよ)
(Ready yet? Not yet!)
泣きじゃくった声で
With a sobbing voice,
(もういいかい？ まーだだよ)
(Ready yet? Not yet!)
笑う君が見えた
I saw you smiling.
(もういいかい？ まーだだよ)
(Ready yet? Not yet!)
幕は上がりだした
The curtain has started to rise.
(もういいかい？ もういいよ)
(Ready yet? Ready now!)
色付けていく ここから
I'll start adding color from here.
はい！ということで
All right! So with that...
始まりましたー！
It has officially begun!
風真いろは 生誕ライブ 2026
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026
スタート！みんな、こんばんは！
starts now! Good evening, everyone!
見てるー？
Are you watching?
はい、ということで、本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
All right, today's official hashtag is this right here!
こちらね、みんないっぱいポストしていっぱいかっこいいとこ撮ってくださいね！頼むよ！
Post lots of tweets and take plenty of cool screenshots! I'm counting on you!
この風真いろはがイケメンであることを世の中に知らしめられるのは、お前たちだけなので！
Because you guys are the only ones who can show the world how cool Kazama Iroha is!
よろしくお願いします！
So please make it happen!
はい！そして、今回のライブ、タイトルがついております！
Yes! And for this live stream, we have an official title!
Wind Trailsというタイトルがついておりますが...
It's titled "Wind Trails"...
そのまま訳して、結構お気づきの方も多かったんですが...
Direct translation aside, many of you probably already figured it out...
「風の軌跡」という意味を込めて付けさせていただき...
I chose it to mean "Traces of the Wind"...
今回のライブ、色々頑張って考えさせていただきました！
and worked really hard to plan out everything for this live!
なので、最後まで楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
So I'd be super happy if you enjoy it all the way to the end!
そして1曲目！「かくれんぼ」歌わせていただきました！どうだったかなー？
And for the first song, I sang "Kakurenbo"! How was it?
今日、室内ライブだと思ったでしょ？
You thought today's live was indoors, didn't you?
見てー！
Look!
曲中にドームが開きましたー！イェーイ！
The dome roof opened up during the song! Yay!
すごい！
Isn't that awesome?
やっぱね、なかなか現地ライブって出来てもさ、青空の下で歌ってることってないので...
Even when we do real live concerts, we rarely get to sing under an open blue sky...
いつか俺たちとお前たちの次元が混ざり合って、空の下で歌えるような世界が来るかもしれないけど...
Someday, a world might come where our dimensions overlap and we can sing under the open sky together...
やってみたくてね、今回は空の下で歌うっていうこの演出をやらせていただきましたー！
But since I really wanted to try it, I put together this stage effect to sing under the sky!
めっちゃいいでしょ？
Pretty cool, right?
ステージもめっちゃかっこいいんで！
Plus, the stage looks super cool too!
今日はね、多分いっぱい見る機会あると思いますが...
You'll probably get to see plenty of it today...
ゆっくり隅から隅まで！
so take your time looking at every single corner!
アーカイブ勢もね、きっといると思うんで、いろんな細部こだわってるんで、細かく見てくださいね！
I know there will be archive viewers too, so please pay close attention to all the detailed work!
ということで、お水飲んでもいいですかね？
So with that... is it okay if I take a water break?
お水を...
Let me just get some water...
やめろ！俺の頭をいじ... やめ...
Stop it! Don't mess with my head... stop...
頭をいじくり回されて、ヘッドセットになりました。
My head got fiddled with, and now I have a headset on!
水が... 今日、水を用意してくれたんだよね！
And the water... they prepared water for me today!
みんなに見える水！
Water that all of you can see!
うまい！
Delicious!
うますぎる！この振りはちょっと怒られそうだからもうできないけど、うますぎる！
So good! I'll probably get scolded if I keep doing this movement, but it's so good!
うまいなー。
So refreshing...
これであと1時間やるか... そんなわけにもいかないんで...
Should we just do this for another hour? Well, we can't do that...
一回ね、ちょっと返して...
Let me hand this back real quick...
それじゃあ、水分補給もさせてもらって、息も整ったんで...
All right, now that I've hydrated and caught my breath...
はい！次の曲早速行っていきたいと思います！
yes! Let's jump straight into the next song!
それでは、次の曲聴いてください。「白線」
Now then, please listen to the next song: "Hakusen"!
澄み渡った空に白線 あの地平を超えて
White contrails in the clear blue sky, reaching far beyond that horizon.
始まりはちょっと軽い期待で その欠片そっとポケットしまって
It started with small, humble hopes, tucked away quietly in my pocket.
屋上 遠い空の向こう見ていた
From the rooftop, I gazed far beyond the distant sky.
この足でどこにいけるかなんて わかってないけどわかってるんだ
Where these feet can carry me, I may not know, yet deep down I do.
白昼 淡い月に手をのばした
Reaching my hand out toward the faint daytime moon.
かすれたエコー でも答えはもう はじめからちゃんと持っていたんだよ
A faded echo, yet the answer was already within me right from the start.
メイビー この想いは
Maybe this feeling inside...
マスビー 熱を増して ほらね、飛べるんだ
must be growing hotter, look, I can truly fly!
もっと高く高くまで 羽ばたいてみたい
Higher and higher into the sky, I want to spread my wings and soar!
今日に未来色の軌道描いて 地平の先まで
Tracing a future-colored trail into today, all the way past the horizon.
届かない歌はない 迷いはいらない
There's no song that won't reach, no need for any doubt!
どんな世界も瞬間も揺るがない アイが在るから
Neither the world nor the moment will shake, because love is right here.
澄み渡った空に白線
White contrails in the clear blue sky.
不安と期待のアンビバレント でも声はもう気づいてる
An ambivalent mix of fear and hope, but my voice already knows.
もっと高く高く高く飛んでいける！
I can fly higher, higher, and higher!
途切れ途切れの一縷でも
Even if it's just a broken, faint ray of hope...
紡いでたら「一途」に変わったよ
When I kept spinning them, they turned into "singleminded devotion."
あたりさわりない言葉じゃ
With harmless, safe words alone,
覆いきれないほどのマイワールド
my world is too vast to be covered up.
明日で呼ぶ声の持ち主は
The one whose voice calls out in tomorrow
他でもないあなただった
was none other than you.
言えないでいるその言葉も
Even those words I've kept unsaid,
「言葉」だと足りないだけ
"words" alone just aren't enough.
掴んだもの 落としたもの
What I've grasped, what I've dropped,
転んだって立って見えた視界から
from the view I saw after falling and standing back up,
ロックユー！解き放って
Lock you! Unleash it!
フォーユー！響きだして
For you! Start resounding!
景色変えてゆく
changing the scenery.
まだ遠く遠くまで広がった空に
Into the sky spreading far, far away,
やっと踏み出すこの一歩なんてちっぽけだけど
this single step I finally take may be tiny, but...
届かない場所へと続いていく
It continues on toward an unreachable place.
どんな風に雨に消えない白線を描く
Drawing a white line that won't fade in any wind or rain,
もっと高く高くまで羽ばたいていたい
I want to keep fluttering higher and higher!
そして彼方色で繋ぐリード
And with the colors of beyond, connecting this lead,
智星で待ってて
wait for me at the star of wisdom.
もう願いに嘘はない ここが好き！
There are no lies in my wish anymore, I love it here!
どんな世界も瞬間も輝く 愛が在るから
Any world and any moment shines because love exists here.
今はただ想うこと言えばいい 「愛しているよ！」
Now I just need to say what I feel: "I love you!"
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line in the clear sky,
不安と期待のアンビバレント
an ambivalence of anxiety and expectation.
でも「君」はもう気づいてる
But "you" already noticed,
もっと高く高く高く飛んでいける！
we can fly higher, higher, and higher!
もっとー
More...
鏡よ教えて 私の証はどこにあるのだろう
Tell me, mirror, where is the proof of my existence?
分からない 分からないよ
I don't know, I really don't know.
周りと比べたってさ 虚しくなるだけ
Comparing myself to others only leaves me feeling empty.
あのノイズが耳鳴りのように 涙を奪う
That noise steals my tears like ringing in my ears.
切り取った風景を道標にしよう
Let's make this captured scenery our signpost.
そうだ 傷ついた感情も連れて行くから
That's right, because I'll take even my hurt emotions along.
ずっと響くカンパネラ 新しい未来を感じてる
The echoing campanella... I feel a brand new future.
怖くたって進むしかないでしょ
Even if I'm scared, we have no choice but to move forward, right?
遠くまで
Far away,
届けこの祈りを光となれ
reach out, this prayer, become the light!
もっと もっと 少しずつでもいい 私という答えを
More and more, even little by little is okay, the answer that is me...
もっとー
More...
夜空よ教えて 私の証は輝けるのかな
Tell me, night sky, can the proof of my existence shine?
見つけたい 見つけたいよ
I want to find it, I really want to find it!
誰かの決めた枠は苦しくなるだけ
A frame set by someone else only makes things painful.
ねぇ ノイズも力に変えるよ 心の満ち欠け
Hey, I'll turn even noise into strength, the waxing and waning of my heart.
錆びついた運命の歯車を回そう
Let's turn the rusted gears of fate.
ほら 着飾った感情は脱ぎ捨てているから
Look, because I'm stripping away these dressed-up emotions,
そっと紡ぐシンフォニー 叶えたい願いを信じてる
gently weaving a symphony, I believe in the wish I want to come true.
胸を張って歌うしかないでしょ 全力で
We have no choice but to sing with our heads held high, with all our power!
もっと もっと やがて希望の歌に変わる日まで
More and more, until the day it finally turns into a song of hope.
もっと もっと 悩みながらでいい 全てが宝物
More and more, it's okay to worry along the way, everything is a treasure.
いつの日かこの声を受け取ってくれたなら
If someday you accept this voice of mine,
この言葉を君に もう大丈夫 一人じゃない 強い想いを
I'll give these words to you: "It's alright now, you're not alone," connecting strong feelings...
繋ぐよ 一歩踏み出してみた 優しく世界は微笑む 高鳴る気持ちに身を任せて
I took a step forward, and the world gently smiles; surrendering to this surging emotion, come on, let's go!
響くカンパネラ
Resonating Campanella,
新しい未来を感じてる
I'm feeling a new future.
怖くたって進むしかないでしょ？
Even if I'm scared, I have to move forward, right?
遠くまで
To far away...
もっと もっと
(More, more)
届けこの祈りよ光となれ
Deliver this prayer of mine, become the light!
もっと もっと
More, more,
少しずつでもいい「私」という答えを
even little by little is fine, the answer called "myself".
もっと...
More...
雨とペトラ
[Rain and Petra]
誰かが言った いつか空は灰になって落ちるって
Someone said that one day the sky would turn to ash and fall.
妄想の世の中で 日々を喰らっている
In this world of delusions, I'm devouring the days.
境界線を引いてしまうのも 共感覚のせいにして
Blaming drawing a boundary line on sensory sensitivity,
街の灯の海で 居場所を探している
I'm searching for where I belong in the sea of city lights.
どこへ行くにもこの足は
No matter where I go, these feet of mine
退屈に染まって動かない
are stained with boredom and won't move.
少しだけ先の景色が
I just want to see the scenery
見たいだけなのにな
just a little bit further ahead...
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと 頬を濡らしてしまう
If it rains, if it rains, I'm sure it'll wet my cheeks.
枯れてしまった色でさえ 愛おしくなるのに
Even the withered colors become dear to me, yet...
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったらもっと 遠く霞んでしまう
If I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, it'll blur even further away.
うるさくなった雨の音 笑い飛ばしてくれ
The sound of the rain has gotten so loud, laugh it off!
誰かが言った いつか溜息は 夜に化けて歌を歌う
Someone said that one day, my sighs would turn into night and sing songs.
妄想の世の中で 日々を喰らっていよう
In this world of delusions, let's devour the days.
優しい嘘をなぞったせいで 離れる声に気付かない
Because I traced kind lies, I didn't notice the voice drifting away.
溶けた月が足元に落ちて 静かに揺れていた
The melted moon fell at my feet, swaying quietly.
夜が降ったら 夜が降ったらきっと 今日を責めてしまう
If night falls, if night falls, I'm sure I'll blame today.
満たされない日々の底で 夢を見ているだけ
At the bottom of unfulfilled days, I'm just dreaming.
目を逸らしても 目を逸らしてもずっと
Even if I look away, even if I look away, always...
後悔と灰の隙間 取り残されてしまう前に 手を伸ばしてくれ
Before I'm left behind in the gap between regret and ash, reach out your hand!
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと 雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと
If it rains, if it rains, I'm sure... If it rains, if it rains, I'm sure...
湿るアスファルトを背に映して 俯いた
Reflecting the damp asphalt on my back, I looked down.
独りぼっちで また明日に期待をして
All alone, expecting something of tomorrow again.
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと 頬を濡らしてしまう
If it rains, if it rains, I'm sure it'll wet my cheeks.
枯れてしまった色でさえ 愛おしくなるのに
Even the withered colors become dear to me, yet...
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったらもっと 遠く霞んでしまう
If I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, it'll blur even further away.
うるさくなった雨の音 笑い飛ばしてくれ
The sound of the rain has gotten so loud, laugh it off!
群青讃歌
[Gunjo Sanka]
繋がっていたいと信じられる言葉
Words that make me believe I want to stay connected,
だってもう昨日の僕らにおさらば
because it's already goodbye to who we were yesterday.
青い春を過ごした 遠い稲妻
A distant flash of lightning during our green youth,
さっと泣いて 前だけを向けたら
if I could just cry it out and look forward,
きっとどんなに楽になれていたろうな
I'm sure it would have been so much easier.
この心を揺らした 一縷の望みは
The ray of hope that shook this heart of mine...
ないものねだりは辞めた 未完成人間
I stopped wishing for what I don't have; an incomplete human being.
素晴らしき世界だけが 答えを握ってる
Only this wonderful world holds the answer.
諦めてしまうほど この先たくさんの
So many regrets lie ahead on this path...
後悔が君を待ってるけど
...enough to make you want to give up, waiting for you,
もうない 迷いはしないよ
but no more, I won't hesitate anymore.
この傷も愛しく 思えてしまうほど
So much so that even these scars feel dear to me,
重ねてしまうよ 不格好なまんまでいいから
I'll keep adding to them; it's fine even if it's clumsy.
不格好なまんまでいいから
It's fine even if it's clumsy.
その歩幅で
At your own pace,
声轟かせてくれ
let your voice resound.
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embracing expectation and anxiety in equal measure,
君と今を紡ぐ 未来照らして
illuminating the future as I weave the present with you.
顔も名前も知らない僕たちが
We, who know neither each other's faces nor names,
たった1つの音をかき鳴らす
strum out a single sound.
いたずらみたいな奇跡のような刹那
A moment like a mischievous miracle,
あっという間に流れる時が
time flows past in the blink of an eye,
ありのままで在り続ける怖さが
and the fear of remaining just as I am...
失った時間は取り戻せないけれど
We can't bring back the time we lost, but...
過去を振り返ってばかりじゃ 泣いたっていいんだ
If we just keep looking back at the past... it's okay to cry.
悔しさと痛みだけが 君を肯定するから
Because only the frustration and pain validate who you are.
大人になったら 忘れてしまうの
Will we forget when we grow up?
君との約束をした場所は もうない 覚えていたいよ
The place where I made a promise with you is gone now, but I want to remember it.
思い出も愛しく 思えてしまうほど
So much so that even memories feel precious,
重ねてしまうよ 不格好なまんまでいいから
I'll keep layering them; it's fine even if it's clumsy.
その声はどこまでも鳴り響いて
That voice rings out everywhere.
確かな理由を抱いてここまで来たんだ
Holding onto a certain reason, we made it all the way here.
まだ終わらない旅路なんだ
This journey isn't over yet.
いつしか想いは形になる
Someday, our feelings will take shape.
この真っ白に染まる朝
This morning that turns pure white...
忘れられないまま だから
...still unable to forget. That's why...
諦めてしまうほど この先たくさんの
So many regrets lie ahead on this path...
もうない 迷いはしないよ
...no more, I won't hesitate anymore.
かけがえのないもの 溢れてしまうよ
Irreplaceable things overflow within me.
答えは君のその手の中に
The answer is right inside your hands.
離さないで
Don't let go.
物語は一歩前へ
The story takes a step forward.
諦めてしまうほど この先たくさんの
So many regrets lie ahead on this path...
後悔が君を待ってるけど
...enough to make you want to give up, waiting for you,
もうない 迷いはしないよ
but no more, I won't hesitate anymore.
この傷も愛しく 思えてしまうほど
So much so that even these scars feel dear to me,
重ねてしまうよ 不格好なまんまでいいから
I'll keep adding to them; it's fine even if it's clumsy.
走れ その歩幅で
Run at your own pace,
走れ 声轟かせてくれ
run and let your voice resound.
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embracing expectation and anxiety in equal measure,
君と今を紡ぐ 未来照らして
illuminating the future as I weave the present with you.
六兆年と一夜物語
[Song Title: Six Trillion Years and Overnight Story]
名もない時代の集落の
In an unnamed village of an unnamed era,
名もない幼い少年の
an unnamed young boy's...
誰も知らないおとぎ話
...fairytale that nobody knows.
生まれついた時から
From the moment I was born,
忌み子 鬼の子として
as a cursed child, a demon's child,
その身に余る罰を受けた
I received punishment more than my body could bear.
悲しいことは何もないけど
There is nothing sad, but
夕焼け小焼け 手を引かれてさ
hand in hand in the sunset, I am led.
知らない 知らない 僕は何にも知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything.
叱られた後の優しさも
Not the kindness after being scolded,
雨上がりの手の温もりも
nor the warmth of hands after the rain.
でも本当は 本当は 本当は 本当に寒いんだ
But the truth is, the truth is, the truth is, it's really cold.
死なない 死なない 僕は何で死なない？
I won't die, I won't die, why won't I die?
夢の一つも見れないくせに
Even though I can't even dream a dream.
誰も知らない おとぎ話は
A story that nobody knows
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was sucked into the sunset and disappeared.
吐き出すような暴力と
With the violence that seems to be spat out
蔑んだ目の毎日に
and every day of scornful eyes,
君はいつしかそこに立ってた
you were standing there before I knew it.
話しかけちゃ駄目なのに
Even though you shouldn't have spoken to me,
「君の名前が知りたいな」
"I want to know your name."
ごめんね 名前も 舌も無いんだ
Sorry, I have no name, and no tongue either.
僕の居場所は 何処にも無しの
Even though I have nowhere to belong,
「一緒に帰ろう」 手を引かれてさ
"Let's go home together," hand in hand, I am led.
知らない 知らない 僕は何にも知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything.
君はもう子供じゃないことも
That you are no longer a child either,
慣れない 他人の 手の温もりは
the warmth of another person's hands that I'm not used to,
ただ本当に 本当に 本当に 本当のことなんだ
is truly, truly, truly the truth.
やめない やめない 君は何でやめない？
Don't stop, don't stop, why won't you stop?
見つかれば殺されちゃうくせに
Even though you'll be killed if you're found.
雨上がりに 忌み子がふたり
Two cursed children after the rain
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
were sucked into the sunset and disappeared.
日が暮れて夜が明けて
The sun sets, the night dawns,
遊び疲れて捕まって
exhausted from playing, caught.
こんな世界 僕と君以外
In such a world, other than me and you,
皆いなくなればいいのにな
if only everyone would disappear,
if only everyone would disappear.
知らない 知らない 声が聞こえてさ
I don't know, I don't know, a voice is heard,
僕と君以外の全人類
and all of humanity, other than me and you,
抗う間もなく 手を引かれてさ
resisting, without a moment to spare, hand in hand, I am led,
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was sucked into the sunset and disappeared.
知らない 知らない 僕は何にも知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything.
これからのことも 君の名も
About the future, or even your name.
今は 今は これでいいんだと
Now, now, I think it's fine this way,
ただ本当に 本当に 本当に 本当に思うんだ
I truly, truly, truly, truly think so.
知らない 知らない あの耳鳴りは
I don't know, I don't know, that ringing in my ears
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was sucked into the sunset and disappeared.
風を追いかけて
Chasing the wind,
雨を抜けて
passing through the rain,
咲き誇れ
bloom in full glory!
夜風に揺られている
Swaying in the night breeze,
触れないように怯えている
fearful of touching,
ずっと雨に濡らされている
constantly drenched in the rain,
まだどうしたって凍えてしまったんだ
I still froze no matter what.
誰か この声に応答して
Someone, please respond to this voice!
ほどけないままの跡を
Leaving the unresolved marks behind...
今 見逃せないくらい
Right now, so vividly it can't be missed,
綺麗に咲かせてたいんだ
I want to make it bloom beautifully.
光っていた未来が ずっと待っていた世界が
The shining future, the world I've been waiting for,
きらめく音の中にあるなら
if it lies within these sparkling sounds,
最低で最悪な涙も
even the worst and most awful tears,
言い出せないでいる声も
and the voices unable to speak out,
連れて行きたいんだ 全部
I want to take them all with me!
不完全な毎日の
Of these incomplete days,
一瞬の欠片たちが
the momentary fragments,
重なってこんな歌を奏でたなら
overlapping to play a song like this...
それは言葉だけじゃ届かない距離も
Even distances unreachable by words alone,
きっと飛び越えて結ぶ
will surely be leaped across and bound together.
輪を描いて行く
Drawing a circle as it goes.
刻んで 進行のペース上げてく
Mark the beat, pick up the pace of our progress,
バラバラになっても 気取って浮いて
Even if we fall apart, put on airs and stay afloat.
ベロを回せ グルーヴとランデブーしてく
Work that tongue, rendezvous with the groove.
こんがらがる スマンナイ持て
Getting all tangled up, hold onto your boredom,
ハイになって踊れ G-Typeは繊細だから
Get high and dance, because G-Type is delicate.
音符 マイナスの稲妻 泣いて
Musical notes, lightning of negatives, crying out—
声を枯らせ 泥だらけになっても生きていたい
Shout your voice hoarse! Even covered in mud, I want to live!
今夜 あの空で合流して
Tonight, let's meet up in that sky,
朝が満ちるまで
Until the morning fills the night,
それぞれの星を探そう
Let's search for our own stars.
ねぇ 今
Hey, right now,
同じこと思っていたんだって
Were you thinking the exact same thing?
ほら
See,
話さなくても分かり合えた
We could understand each other without words.
ああ
Ah,
こんな嬉しさをずっと待っていた気がした
I felt like I've been waiting for a joy like this forever.
光っていた未来がずっと待っていた
The shining future was waiting all along,
世界が煌めいて目の前にあるから
Because a sparkling world lies right before my eyes.
瞬きの刹那まで
Until the blink of an eye,
このストーリーの最後まで
Until the very end of this story,
輝く花でいたいんだ
I want to remain a shining flower.
不完全な私たちの一瞬の欠片たちが
The fleeting pieces of our imperfect selves
重なってこんな歌を奏でた
Overlapped to play a song like this.
それは夢見るだけじゃ叶わない思いをずっと
Thoughts that won't come true by dreaming alone,
新しくしていく
Continuously making them anew,
ずっと追いかけていこう
Let's keep chasing them forever.
風を割って
Cutting through the wind,
雨を抜けて
Passing through the rain,
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory,
満天の空へ
Into the sky full of stars.
ノンブレス・オブリージュ
[Non-Breath Oblige]
世界中のすべての人間にかわいがられるなんて 気持ち悪いよ
Being liked by every single human in the world is disgusting,
だけど一つになれない教室で 君と二人 手を繋いでいたいの
But in a classroom where we can't become one, I want to hold hands with you.
数の暴力に白旗をあげて 悪感情を殺してハイチーズ
Surrendering to the violence of numbers, killing bad feelings, say "Cheese!"
ポストトゥルースの甘いディープキス エロく歪んでるラブアンドピース
A sweet deep kiss of post-truth, erotically distorted love and peace.
自己中の光線銃 乱射する強者のナンセンス
Nonsense of the strong, firing wildly with self-centered ray guns.
オートクチュールで作る 殺しのライセンス
A license to kill made with haute couture.
分断を生んじゃった椅子取りゲーム
A game of musical chairs that created division,
無痛分娩で授かるベイブ
A babe born through painless delivery,
壮大な内輪ノリを歴史と呼ぶ
Calling grand inside jokes "history."
生きたいが死ねと言われ
Wanting to live, but being told to die,
死にたいが生きてと言われ
Wanting to die, but being told to live,
生きたいが死ねと言われ
Wanting to live, but being told to die,
死にたいが生きてと言われ
Wanting to die, but being told to live.
幸せ自慢はダメ？
Is boasting happiness forbidden?
不幸嘆いてもダメ？
Is lamenting unhappiness forbidden too?
図々しい言葉を避け 明るい未来のため
Avoiding brazen words for the sake of a bright future,
「この世には息もできない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are so many people in this world who can't even breathe."
あちらが立てば こちらが立たず 譲り 奪い 守り 行き違い
If you satisfy one side, the other suffers; giving, taking, protecting, misunderstanding.
地雷原で立ち止まり 大人しく犬になるんだワン
Stopping in a minefield, meekly becoming a dog. Woof!
ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・オブリージュ I love you
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige, I love you.
息苦しい日々の水面下
Beneath the surface of suffocating days,
ゆらゆらと煙る血の花
A flower of blood sways in smoke.
ぼくらはコンプレックスを武器に争う
We fight using our complexes as weapons.
それぞれの都合と自由のため
For our own convenience and freedom,
息を止めることを強制する
Forcing each other to hold our breath.
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
Suffocating, suffocating, suffocating, suffocating,
生きたいが死ねと言われ
Wanting to live, but being told to die,
死にたいが生きてと言われ
Wanting to die, but being told to live,
生きたいが死ねと言われ
Wanting to live, but being told to die,
死にたいが生きてと言われ
Wanting to die, but being told to live.
正当防衛と言ってチェーンソーを振り回す
Swinging a chainsaw under the guise of self-defense,
まともな人たちが怖いよ
"Sane" people are terrifying.
春欄漫 日々だんだん 大事なものが消えていくよ
Spring in full bloom, day by day, precious things keep disappearing.
「この世には愛も知らない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are so many people in this world who don't even know love."
共感 羨望 嫉妬 坂から転がり 黒い涙がこぼれ落ち
Empathy, envy, jealousy rolling down the slope, black tears falling down,
醜い感情 吐き出し 真っ白い鳥になるんだな
Spewing out hideous emotions, becoming a pure white bird.
ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・オブリージュ I love you
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige, I love you.
深海魚と泳ぐ氷点下
Swimming with deep-sea fish below freezing point,
見上げているザラメの星
Looking up at stars made of coarse sugar.
ぼくらは直接 直接 手を下さないまま
Without getting our hands dirty directly,
想像力を奪い 液晶越しに
Robbing imagination, through liquid crystal screens,
息の根を止めて安心する
Cutting off the breath of life and feeling relieved.
ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・オブリージュ I love you
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige, I love you.
それぞれの都合と自由のため 息を―
For our own convenience and freedom, holding our—
息を止めること
Forcing to hold my breath,
強制する
forcing it.
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
Breath is clogged, breath is clogged, breath is clogged...
息を止める 息を止める 息を止める 息を止める
Holding my breath, holding my breath...
ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・オブリージュ
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige
I love you
それぞれの好きを守るため
To protect what each of us loves,
君と僕等で 呼吸する
you and I breathe together.
酸素足りな... 酸素足りない...
Not enough oxygen... Not enough oxygen...
酸素足りないんですけど...
I don't have enough oxygen, but...
はい！
Okay!
2曲続けてやらせていただきました！
I performed two songs back-to-back!
はい、いかがだったでしょうか？
Well, how was it?
昨日の配信で話したんですけど、
I mentioned this in yesterday's stream,
あの、一部人間じゃないヤツがあるって言ってたのが、
when I said some songs weren't meant for humans,
この『ノンブレス・オブリージュ』と、
it was "Non-breath oblige" and...
先ほどソロでやらせていただいた『毒チョコネットとイチゴの物語』でした！
the song I sang solo earlier, 'Doku Choco Net to Ichigo no Monogatari'!
はい... ちょっと、純粋にすごく心配だったんですけど、
Yeah... I was honestly really worried about it,
なんとかね、できてよかったと、今すごい安心で...
but I'm so relieved that I pulled it off...
安心で今震えております！
I'm trembling with relief right now!
はい！というわけで、ここまでたくさん見ていただきましたが、
Alright! So, you've watched a lot up to this point,
皆さん、いかがでしょうかー？
how is everyone enjoying it?
ゲストもね、めっちゃ来てもらって、
We had so many guests come on stage, too!
AZKiちゃんと、あとミオ先輩、フレア先輩、あと桃鈴ねね先輩ね！
AZKi-chan, Mio-senpai, Flare-senpai, and Momosuzu Nene-senpai!
はい、ありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you so much!
あの、本当にみんなと歌ってみたかった曲を、
Honestly, these were songs I really wanted to sing with everyone,
自分が好きなやつを、
songs that I personally love,
「この人にこれを歌ってるところを聞きたい」っていう気持ちで、
picking them thinking "I want to hear this person sing this,"
選んで、一緒にね、やらせていただきました！
and I got to perform them together with them!
本当にありがとうございます！先輩たちありがとうー！
Thank you so much! Thank you, senpais!
ちょっと、一口水飲んでもいいかな？水を飲ませてください！
Can I take a sip of water? Please let me drink some water!
はいっと...
All right...
はい、ちょっと落ち着きました。
Okay, I've calmed down a bit now.
はい、ということで、まだまだ続くんでね、次の曲行っていきたいと思うんですけど、
Alright, so there's still more to come, and I'd like to move on to the next song...
次の曲は、あの、昨日のトークでもめっちゃリクエスト上がってて、
The next song had so many requests during yesterday's chat,
で、その前からずっとリクエスト上がってて、
and even before that, people kept requesting it,
「いやこれ生誕ライブでやりたいなー」ってことでずっととっておいた曲です！
so I kept saving it, thinking "I want to do this at my Birthday Live!"
なので楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです！
So I hope you enjoy it!
それでは、次の曲聴いてください。
Now then, please listen to the next song.
『ray』
"ray"
お別れしたのはもっと 前のことだったような
It feels like it was much longer ago that we parted
悲しい光は封じ込めて 踵すり減らしたんだ
Locking away the sad light, I wore down my heels
君といた時は見えた 今は見えなくなった
I could see it when I was with you, but now I can't
透明な彗星をぼんやりと でもそれだけ探している
Vaguely searching for that transparent comet, but that's all I'm looking for
しょっちゅう唄を歌ったよ その時だけのメロディーを
I sang songs all the time, melodies unique to those moments
寂しくなんか無かったよ ちゃんと寂しくなれたから
I wasn't lonely at all, because I was able to properly feel lonely
いつまでどこまでなんて 正常か異常かなんて
Until when, how far, whether it's normal or abnormal...
考える暇も無いくらい 歩くのは大変だ
Walking is so tough, I don't even have time to think about it
楽しい方がずっといいよ ごまかして笑っていくよ
Having fun is so much better, I'll fake it and keep smiling
大丈夫だ あの痛みは 忘れたって消えやしない
It's okay, even if I forget that pain, it won't disappear
理想で作った道を 現実が塗り替えていくよ
Reality keeps rewriting the path I built with ideals
思い出はその軌跡の上で 輝きになって残っている
On that track, memories remain as a brilliant glow
お別れしたのは何で 何のためだったんだろうな
Why did we part ways? What was it all for, I wonder?
悲しい光が
The sad light...
悲しい光が僕の影を
Sad light stretches my shadow
前に長く伸ばしている
far out in front of me.
時々熱が出るよ
Sometimes I run a fever,
時間がある時眠るよ
and I sleep when I have time.
夢だと解るその中で
Knowing it's a dream, in the middle of it,
君と会ってからまた行こう
let me set off again after meeting with you.
晴天とは程遠い
Far from a clear blue sky,
終わらない暗闇にも
even in endless darkness,
星を思い浮かべたなら
if you imagine the stars,
すぐ銀河の中だ
you're instantly inside the galaxy.
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry much anymore,
靴を新しくしても
or get new shoes,
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
it's okay, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
...won't disappear even if I forget it.
伝えたかった事がきっとあったんだろうな
There must have been things I wanted to tell you.
恐らくありきたりなんだろうけど
They were probably cliché, but...
こんなにも
...even so...
お別れした事は
Saying goodbye...
出会った事と繋がっている
...is connected to having met.
あの透明な彗星は
That transparent comet...
透明だから無くならない
...won't disappear because it's transparent.
〇✕△どれかなんて
Whether it's right, wrong, or somewhere between,
みんなと比べてどうかなんて
or how it compares to everyone else,
確かめるまでも無いほど 生きるの最高だ
living is the absolute best, without needing to check.
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry much anymore,
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll keep glossing over it with a smile.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
It's okay, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
...won't disappear even if I forget it.
大丈夫だ この光の始まりには
It's okay, at the beginning of this light,
君がいる
you are there.
はい、ということで、rayでした！
Alright, and that was "ray"!
あー、どうでしたでしょうか？
Ah, how was it?
めっちゃ、え、エモーい、エモーい
It felt so... uh, emotional, emotional...
感じになりましたね。
...vibes, didn't it?
はい。ちょっと一瞬水飲んでいいですか？
Yes. Can I drink some water for a second?
ん。
Mm.
ごめん。
Sorry.
飲んでも飲んでも減らない水。いいだろ、風真いろは特製だぜ。
Water that never decreases no matter how much I drink. Pretty cool, right? It's Kazama Iroha's special.
よいしょ、ちょっと待って。
Up we go, hold on a sec.
よし！はい。
Alright! Okay.
というわけで、次のね、曲に行きたいと思うんですけど、
So then, I'd like to move on to the next song...
ま、あの昨日の朝枠でちょっと匂わせおいたんですが、
Well, as I hinted at during yesterday's morning stream...
え、本日ですね、あの、視聴者参加型3D生ライブとなっておりまして、
...today's stream is actually an audience-participatory 3D live performance!
はい。今回はですね、皆さんに投票をしていただいて、次に歌う曲、
Yes! This time, we're having all of you vote on the next song...
決めたいと思います！
...that I'll sing!
それでは、テロップどうぞ！
Now then, on-screen prompt, please!
ジャジャーン！
Ta-da!
えー、
Um...
ANIMAか、ただ声一つ。どっちか。
"ANIMA" or "Tada Koe Hitosu". Which one?
で、投票が少なかった方もこの後メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブで
And whichever gets fewer votes will be sung in the members-only encore stream afterwards,
歌いますので、よろしくお願いします。
so please stay tuned!
いやー、どちらも名曲で、迷いますよねー。
Man, both are total bangers, so it's tough to choose, right?
今、スタッフの人と、どっちになるかねっていうのを賭けてます。
Right now, the staff and I are betting on which one it'll be.
あの、どっちに賭けてるとか言わないんで、
I won't tell you which one I bet on,
さあ、みんな、これで次回の差し入れが豪華になるか裏で決まるからな。
so whether our next stream snacks get upgraded is being decided right now!
はい！というわけで、早速投票開始していきたいと思います。
Alright! So with that, let me start the voting right away.
大体時間は1分ぐらいですかね？
We'll have about one minute, okay?
それでは、用意、スタート！
Ready... set, go!
届いた？
Did it show up?
今、来たかな？
Is it here now?
あ、来た来た来た来た来た来た！
Ah, it's here, it's here, it's here!
はい、じゃあみんな投票ボタン押してね。
Alright everyone, hit that vote button.
じゃあみんなが投票やってる間にゆっくり
Now, while everyone is voting...
みんなのこと待つために帰るわ、メインステージ。
I'll head back to the main stage to wait for you all.
じゃあ移動ですよー、移動ー！
Alright, moving over! Moving!
はい、というわけで、皆さん
Alright, so, everyone!
投票した？できてる？
Did you vote? Is it done?
どっちかだよ！
Choose one or the other!
両方は…両方はちょっとあれだから、どっちか！
Both... both is a bit tricky, so pick one!
どっちかに指定でお願いします。
Please choose one or the other.
そういえば今なんだかんだこうやって歩かせてもらってますが
By the way, as I'm walking around like this now...
実はね、何気に
Actually, you know...
ファーストミッション衣装がね
my First Mission outfit...
見せるのが、ゆっくり見せるのが初めてだったりするんだけど
Showing it off slowly like this is actually a first!
そうだ、ここでさ、宣伝しとこう。尺稼ぎじゃないよ！
Oh right, let me plug something here. Not stalling!
あの、宣伝ね！このあとメン限でアフターライブがあるんですけど
We have a members-only after-live stream after this...
そのね、時に、もっと
And during that time...
このカッコいいところね、いっぱい見せますので
I'll show you lots more of this cool side of me!
なのでぜひよかったらメン限のアフターライブにもお越しくださいっていう宣伝も入れつつ
So please come check out the member-exclusive stream too!
みんな入れた？
Did everyone vote?
入れた？
Did you vote?
凄いな、これ花道。
This stage runway is so long!
長くない？
Isn't it long?
なが、長くない？
Isn't... isn't it long?
これ現地ライブでもやりたいな。
I wanna do this at an in-person live performance too.
はい、だいぶカッコいい風真いろはさんをいっぱい見せているわけなんですが
Alright, I've been showing off a very cool Kazama Iroha...
いや、でもどっちかなこれ。
Man, I wonder which one it'll be.
ANIMAはね、みんな、設定の通りあの「カッコいい」で
"ANIMA" is, as described, a cool song.
「ただ声一つ」は「しっとり」なんでね
And "Tada Koe Hitotsu" is mellow!
ちょっとこれ好みが分かれると思いますが
So I think preferences will be divided, but...
はい、いや、きっとね、どっちやってみんなカッコいいって言ってくれるよね？
Yeah, no matter which one wins, everyone will say it's cool, right?
言ってくれるよね？
You'll say it, right?
あ、カメラは「言ってくれる」ってことで！
Ah, the camera operator nods "yes"!
はい、というわけでみんな、もう大丈夫かな？
Alright, so is everyone good now?
オッケー？
Okay?
じゃあそろそろ終わっちゃいますからね。
Alright, we're going to wrap it up soon!
早く早く！早く投票してね！
Hurry, hurry! Get your votes in quickly!
終わっ、終わったよね、スタッフさん？
Is it finished? It's finished, right staff?
終わっ、早かった歩くの。
Finished? Was I walking too fast?
終わっ、終わった、終わったのかな？
Is it... is it finished?
あ、なんか終わったらしい！
Ah, looks like it's done!
今、賭けをしているスタッフと睨めっこしてます。
I was just having a staring contest with the staff who placed bets.
それでは！
And now!
結果発表タイム！
Results announcement time!
ドゥルドゥルドゥルドゥルドゥルドゥル…
Drumroll...
デダン！
Tada!
アンケートの結果、ANIMAになったみたいです！
According to the poll results, it looks like it's ANIMA!
あ、これあの、賭けに勝った人の動きです。
Ah, this is the victory pose of someone who won the bet.
うーい！差し入れ期待してます！よっしゃー！
Wheee! Looking forward to those snacks! All right!
というわけで、賭けにも勝ち、皆さんにも選んでいただき、とても有難い限りですね。
So, winning the bet and having everyone choose, I'm truly grateful!
「ただ声一つ」のほうもこのあとメンバーシップ限定で歌いますのでそちらも楽しみに！
I'll also sing "Tada Koe Hitotsu" after this in the members live stream!
というわけで、早速
So then, let me get right to it...
歌っていきましょうか。
Shall we start singing?
それでは聴いてください。「ANIMA」。
Now please listen: ANIMA.
魂の色は
What color is the color of your soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
「もういっそ折れたままで」
"I'd rather stay broken"
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
Enough to discard, enough to run away...
強くないよ
I'm not that strong
ほら もう一度 鼓動 高鳴る
Look, once again, my heartbeat quickens
何が正しいかなんて わからないけど
I don't know what's right, but...
形のないものばかりが 大切になって行く
Things without form keep becoming precious
飾らない言葉だけが
Only unadorned words
強く 結ばれてる
are strongly tied together
また躓いて 転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling again, rolling over, yet still unbreakable
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the color of your soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって
Just getting hurt, pretending to be strong
それでも見つけたいよ 魂のカタチ
Even so, I want to find the shape of my soul
確かめてるよ
I'm making sure of it
深い地の底で一人 扉と鍵を探す
Alone deep underground, searching for the door and key
おとぎ話は
Fairy tales are...
ほら 泡の様に全部消えて
look, disappearing like bubbles completely
葛藤 残像だけ 次の頁へ
Leaving only conflict and afterimages for the next page
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて
Branching leaves extend and part ways
それぞれの道を行く
Each taking their own path
寂しい思い出だけが
Only lonely memories
強く根を張ってる
Have taken deep, strong roots
また貫いて 失って それでも挫けない
Piercing through, losing, yet never giving in
心はどこに 器はどこに
Where is the heart? Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて 抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Left behind, falling away, yet I still want to convey
魂の日々を 魂の意志を
The days of my soul, the will of my soul
ずっと...
Forever...
魂の色は
What color is the soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
What color is the soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
透明な過去に 不透明な明日に
In a transparent past, in an opaque tomorrow
生きるあなたは 何色ですか
Living on, what color are you?
また躓いて 転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling again, rolling, yet never shattering
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt, putting on a tough front, yet I still want to find it
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
Confirming the shape of the soul
ずっと...
Forever...
はい！ということで、ANIMAを歌わせていただきました！
Yes! So, that was my performance of "ANIMA"!
カロリー高い方だったな... お水、水ください！
That song was pretty high calorie... Water, please give me water!
カロリー高い方だった... 危ない。
That was high calorie... That was close.
あ、すみません。あの、ナチュラルにマイクを返すの忘れていました。
Ah, sorry. I naturally forgot to hand back the mic.
やばい、音変になってなかったらいいな。すみません。
Oh no, I hope the audio didn't sound weird. Sorry about that.
ナチュラルに... スタッフさんがっつり手を伸ばしてくれてたのに、疲れすぎてここ硬直してた。
Naturally... even though the staff reached their arms way out, I was so tired my arm just froze up here.
水うまい。偉い水のおかげで生きていけてます。
Water is so good. Thanks to this wonderful water, I'm staying alive.
はい、じゃちょっとこれ返して...
Okay, let me hand this back...
はい。それではですね、ま、ちょっとまだまだ続くんですけど、ここいらで一旦、重大告知タイムをさせていただきたいと思います！
Alright. Well then, we still have a lot more to go, but right about now, I'd like to take a moment for some major announcements!
じゃ、まずはいつものからいっか！じゃ、まずはこちら！
Alright, let's start with the usual! First up, this!
風真いろは 誕生日記念グッズ 2026 出ます！ ドンドンパフパフ〜！
Kazama Iroha Birthday Celebration Goods 2026 are releasing! *drum roll* Ta-da!
いや、なんか良さそうなラインナップですね！
Wow, looks like a great lineup!
はい、今回もとってもこだわったグッズばかりなんで、皆さん楽しみに待っていてほしいです！では1つずつ商品を見ていきましょう！
Yes, these are all items we put a lot of care into this time as well, so please look forward to them! Let's take a look at each product!
まずはこちら！タペストリーが出ます！
First, this one! A tapestry is releasing!
タペストリー、実は個人グッズで出すの超久しぶりなんですよね！イラストはもちぷよ先生描き下ろしで、雨上がりの青空の下で、もうホントにね、このステージみたいな感じでライブをしている風真いろはのイメージで描いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
It's actually been a really long time since I released a tapestry as solo merch! The illustration was specially drawn by Mochipuyo-sensei, depicting Kazama Iroha performing live under a post-rain blue sky, right on a stage like this! Thank you so much!
いや、めっちゃいいですよね！飾ってね！
Wow, it turned out so great! Please hang it up!
続いてはこちら！フード付きタオル！
Next is this! A hooded towel!
はい、タペストリーと同じイラストのフード付きタオルです。フード部分はぽこべぇの顔になっており、取り外しが可能となっております。
Yes, it's a hooded towel featuring the same illustration as the tapestry. The hood features Pokobee's face and is detachable.
いや、なんか、この間ね、ホロックスのライブがあったじゃん？で、なんかダンスの先生に教えてもらったんだけど、なんか風真隊、異様にタオル購入率が良かったらしいな！お前たち、首にいっぱい巻いてくれておらいぞ！
You know, we had the HoloX live concert recently, right? My dance teacher told me that apparently Kazama-tai had an abnormally high towel purchase rate! Good job, everyone, wrapping them around your necks!
なもんで
So,
あの、これでジニンぽこべぇごっこができるようになります
with this, you can play pretend as Jinin Pokobe!
ジニンぽこべぇごっこをしたい方
If you want to play pretend as Jinin Pokobe,
ま、取り外してそのまま飾りたい方もね、どうぞ
or if you just want to take off the hood and display it, please go ahead!
はい、そしてお次はこちら！
Alright, and next up is this!
ペットボトルホルダー！
Plastic Bottle Holder!
あの、これは風真いろはさんが欲しいの作、作、作りました！
Um, Kazama Iroha made what she personally wanted!
あの、イラストはさめあんこ先生に書いていただきました。可愛いでしょ！
The illustration was drawn by Sameanko-sensei. Isn't it cute?
この真ん中の穴に、あの、ぎゅってペットボトルのところを入れてね
You squeeze the bottle mouth into this hole in the middle,
あの、使うやつです。はい、めっちゃおしゃれです。
and that's how you use it. Yes, it's super stylish!
よかったら使ってください。
Please use it if you'd like.
カバンとかね、つけて持ち運べるんでね
You can attach it to your bag and carry it around.
はい！
Alright!
そしてラストはこちら！
And the last one is this!
はい！
Yes!
実は地味になかったセーラー服Ver.の風真いろはのぬいぐるみ！
A Kazama Iroha plushie in her sailor uniform, which surprisingly didn't exist until now!
なんとボイス付きです！
And surprisingly, it comes with audio voice recorded!
こちらもさめあんこ先生に原案考えていただきました
Sameanko-sensei designed the original draft for this as well.
レインポンチョを着た声が出るぬいぐるみです
It's a voice-playing plushie wearing a rain poncho.
ま、お手手握りしめると音が出るらしいぞ
Well, apparently it makes sound when you squeeze its hands!
今のところはな！はい。
For now at least! Yes.
外出時にカバンなどにつけることもできます
You can also attach it to your bag when going out.
ってボイスなんですけど、なんか天気に関するものを取ったんですよ
And about the recorded voice, I recorded stuff related to the weather!
どんな感じかはまだ流石に言えないけど
I can't say what kind of content it is yet, of course,
だけど、あの、おみくじ感覚で聴いて
but listen to it like a fortune-telling draw,
あの、その天気にならなかったからといって風真いろはを責めないでください
and please don't blame Kazama Iroha if the weather turns out different!
自己責任で、ニギニギしてください
At your own risk, please squeeze it lots!
買ってお楽しみです
Please look forward to it when you buy it!
いっぱいありましたがフルセット見ていきましょう！
There were many items, but let's check out the full set!
こちら！
Here it is!
今回のグッズはですね、生誕のイメージに合わせてフェス風をテーマに作ってみました！
For this merchandise, I designed it with a festival theme in mind for my birthday celebration!
実用性たっぷりだし、これからの季節にぴったりなんで
It's full of practical items and perfect for the coming season,
よかったらよろしくお願いします！
so please check it out if you'd like!
そしてフルセット購入特典は...
And the full set purchase bonus is...
えー、こちら！
Umm, this!
数量限定版あります！
There's a limited quantity version available!
風真いろはの直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージ入りチケット風カード！
A ticket-style card with Kazama Iroha's handwritten signature and foil-stamped duplicate message!
ちょっとおしゃれな感じですね
It feels pretty stylish!
そして通常版には箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りチケット風カードがついてきます
And the regular version comes with a ticket-style card featuring a foil-stamped duplicate signature and message!
さらにどちらにも、えー、ま、ボイスがついてきますね！
Furthermore, both versions come with a voice clip!
はい、「君と雨宿り」というなんかタイトルのボイスがついてくるんですけど
Yes, it comes with a voice clip titled "Sheltering from the Rain with You",
ま、ぶっちゃけあの、気になったら聴いてください
and honestly, please listen to it if you're curious.
ボイス...
The voice...
恥ずかしすぎて死にそうだったからね！
was so embarrassing to record, I almost died!
はい、ということで、ま、シチュエーションボイスですね
Yes, so it's a situation voice clip.
雨宿り系だった気が、なんか恥ずかしがりながら撮った気がします
It was a rain-shelter theme, and I feel like I recorded it while feeling super embarrassed.
そしてグッズは21時カートオープンです！
And the merch cart opens at 21:00!
すみません、あの、生配信につきちょっと時間が押してそうなんですけれど
Sorry, since this is a live stream, time seems to be running a bit over,
あの、ゆっくり買ってねとは言えず...
so I can't really tell you to take your time buying...
頑張ってください！
Good luck!
余裕がない、ごめん！
I've got no leeway here, sorry!
そしてあの、21時からホロメンの多分配信控えてると思うんですけど
And also, other Hololive members probably have streams starting at 21:00,
何も気にしなくていいんです、スタートしてくださいね！
but please don't mind this and go ahead and start!
はい！
Yes!
そして、まだまだあります！
And there's still more!
まだまだ！
Still more!
それがこちら！
And that is this!
はい！新曲ー！イエーイ！
Yes! A new song! Yay!
風真いろはさん、新曲が出ます！
Kazama Iroha is releasing a new song!
タイトルは『風向きエントロピー』
The title is "Kazamuki Entropy".
作詞作曲は「Iroha Step」でもお馴染み40mPさんにしていただきました！
Lyrics and music were written by 40mP, who is also known for "Iroha Step"!
はい！
Yes!
配信後にこちらMVが公開されます！
The Music Video for this will be released right after the stream!
多分こっそり今マネちゃんがプレミア公開に切り替えてくれているはず！
Mane-chan is probably quietly switching it to Premieres right now!
楽曲は0時リリースになっております！
The song track will be released at midnight!
はい！
Yes!
そしてあの、ちょっと気づいた人もいるかもしれないんですけど
And, some of you might have noticed,
ジャケットの文字は風真いろはさんが自分で書きました！はい！
the text on the jacket art was written by Kazama Iroha herself! Yes!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ということで
And so,
もう終わっちゃうんですけど
it's almost time to end,
なんかすごいトレンド2位とかに入ってるっていう連絡を受けました！
but I received a message saying we reached #2 on trending!
くそっ！
Darn!
「あと残り頑張ってくれ」と言いたいけれど
I'd like to say "keep working hard for the rest of it",
でもみんな本当にいっぱいポストしてくれてありがとねー！
but everyone, thank you so much for posting so much!
よし！
Alright!
準備できた？
Are you ready?
大人の準備ができてそうなので
It looks like the staff setup is ready,
早速、新曲！
so without delay, my new song!
歌っていきたいと思います！
I'd like to sing it for you!
が、しかし！今回はちょっと特別なものを用意してきました
However! I've prepared something special this time.
さあ！
Now then!
ゴンドラ！来い！
Gondola! Come here!
おー！リハーサルで見たけど、やっぱいいなこれ！
Ooh! I saw it during rehearsal, but it really is great!
ほい！というわけで
Hoi! So,
みんなポコ兵がいなくて寂しかったでしょ？
everyone was lonely without Pokobe, right?
今年は！ゴンドラになりました！
This year, he became a gondola!
はい！
Yes!
というわけで、早速やっていくんですが
So, we'll get right into it, but...
ドア、オープン！
Door, open!
イエーイ！ほっ！乗っちゃうのー！
Yay! Hop! I'm getting on!
というわけで、早速歌っていきたいと思います！
And so, I'd like to sing right away!
それでは聴いてください
Please listen.
風真いろは、新オリジナル曲『風向きエントロピー』
Kazama Iroha's new original song, "Kazamuki Entropy".
ねえ いつからそこにあったの？
Hey, since when was it right there?
あまりにも近すぎて 気づかなかったよ
It was so close, I didn't even notice.
ずっと 私が生まれた日から
Ever since the day I was born,
そばにいてくれたのにね
you were right by my side.
曖昧で 複雑で 予測不可能で
Vague, complex, and unpredictable,
気まぐれに変わっていく 空の模様
changing on a whim, like the sky's patterns.
想像していたように
Just as I had imagined,
うまく笑えない
I can't smile easily,
だけどそれ以上に
but even more than that,
世界は優しくて
the world is so gentle.
いつか風が生まれた
Someday, a wind was born,
足跡が始まる場所
at the place where footsteps begin.
あの通りに戻って
Returning to that street,
駆け出したとしても
and running out again,
ここに来るんだろう
I'd probably end up here anyway.
この景色も
This scenery, too,
この声も
and these voices, too,
私を彩るすべて
are everything that colors me.
方向なんてまだわからないけど
I still don't know the direction, but
ただ風の吹くままに
I'll just follow wherever the wind blows.
ねぇ いつから気づいていたの？
Hey, when did you notice?
まるで私のこと全部お見通しで
As if you could see right through everything about me.
苦しまぎれに誤魔化した嘘も
Even the desperate lies I used to cover things up,
君にはバレていたのかな
were you able to see right through them?
平凡で退屈で
So ordinary, so boring,
あくびばかりで
nothing but yawning,
変哲のないありふれてる時間
in these plain, everyday moments.
想像していただけじゃ
Just imagining it alone
何も変わらない
wont change a thing,
だけどそれ以上に
but even more than that,
予測していた以上に
even more than I expected,
ほら 新しい風が吹いてきて
look, a new wind has blown in,
不器用な自分が
making my awkward self
やけに愛おしく思えたんだ
feel so strangely dear to me.
いつか風が止んで
Someday when the wind stops,
足跡が途切れた場所
at the place where footsteps fade away,
落とし物探して
searching for lost things,
拾ってみつけだせたから
because I was able to find and pick them up,
ここにいるんだろう
that's why I'm here now.
そっと 髪が揺らめく
Gently, my hair sways.
いつか風が夢見た
The wind once dreamed of
青空と交わる場所
the place where it meets the blue sky.
回り道選んで
Choosing a roundabout path,
迷ってつまずいたとしても
getting lost, even if I stumble,
そこへ行くんだろう
I'll still head over there.
この景色も
This scenery, too,
この声も
and these voices, too,
私を彩るすべて
are everything that colors me.
等身大の手で握りしめて
Holding tight with my true, real hands,
想像以上にずっと自由な速度で
at a speed much freer than imagined,
あぁ 方向なんてまだわからないけど
Ah, I still don't know the direction, but
ただ風の吹くままに
I'll just follow wherever the wind blows.
はい！というわけで、ありがとうございました！
Alright! So with that, thank you so much!
よいしょ、みんなすっかり忘れてると思うけど
Alright, I'm sure everyone completely forgot, but...
今日これから記念撮影しまーす！
today from here on, we're taking a commemorative photo!
そう、お土産があるって言ったでしょ？
Yeah, I told you there'd be souvenirs, right?
これこれ、ちょっと待って、まじで自撮り棒、リハーサルでめっちゃ練習したのに…
This, this, wait a sec. Seriously, even though I practiced with the selfie stick so much in rehearsal...
自撮り棒下手… あ、いい感じいい感じ！
I'm so bad at selfie sticks... Ah, looks good, looks good!
よし、行けそう行けそう！
Alright, looks like we're good!
オッケー！
Okay!
はい！
Yes!
というわけで、皆さん、今日お土産ありって言いましたね！
So, everyone, I mentioned earlier that there would be souvenirs today, right?
そうなんです！
That's right!
今日撮った今この風真がね、自撮り棒で撮った写真が、コンビニで、なんとプリントアウトできます！
The photo Kazama just took right now using the selfie stick can actually be printed out at convenience stores!
すごーい！
That's amazing!
はい、こちらですね、対象店舗FamilyMartさん、LAWSONさん、MINISTOPさんで本日21時から、えー、ネットで事前購入ができます！
Yes, right here! At target stores FamilyMart, Lawson, and Ministop, starting at 21:00 today, you can purchase it online in advance!
えー、お値段がですね、税込300円とのことで、
And the price is 300 yen including tax, and...
印刷できるようになるのは、えー、明日の6月19日、えー、20時からになっております！
...you will be able to print it starting tomorrow, June 19th, at 20:00!
写真にはですね、複製手書きメッセージ、あの、この後書きますんで！
On the photo, I'll add a replicated handwritten message after this!
はい！
Yes!
どんな写真が撮れているか、ちょっと写真下手くそでも怒らないでね！あの、内容は買ってから確認してください！
As for what kind of photo was taken, please don't be mad even if my photo skills are bad! Please check the contents after buying it!
いや、すごいよね！ちょっといち早く皆さんの元に、あの、何か手元に残るライブのね、お土産が用意できればということで、今回やらせていただきました！お土産あります！
Isn't that awesome? We set this up because I really wanted to deliver a physical live souvenir to all of you as quickly as possible! We've got souvenirs for you!
ちょっと皆各自で回収って形で それだけが申し訳ないんですが
I'm sorry that you'll have to go collect them yourselves,
お土産ありますんで
but we have these souvenirs for you,
ぜひ気になったら コンビニでプリントしてみてください！
so if you're interested, please try printing them at a convenience store!
そして コンビニプリント購入できるのは7月21日17時59分までです
Convenience store prints will be available until July 21st at 17:59.
概要欄に 写真こういうの リンクタブにもマネーちゃんがやってくれてると思いますので よろしくお願いします！
Manager-chan has added the links to the photos in the description and link tab, so please check them out!
そしてこの後はですね MVの公開とメンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブありますので そちらも絶対聴いてくだサーイ！
Also, coming up next, we have the MV release and a members-only encore live, so please be sure to check those out as well!
それでは皆さん またお会いしましょう！
Well then, everyone, see you again!
最高の誕生日でした！
It was the best birthday!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!